[circuits crackling]
[♪♪♪]
[automated voice, over P.A.
Please have your ID ready
for your new household battery.
We are low on inventory,
so not everyone in line
will be fortunate enough
to get a replacement
at this time. [crowd groaning]
Well, Percival did ask us
to conserve energy.
I bet I could make it
another day or two if I had to.
Wasn't like this
when Empress Beatrix
was in charge,
that's all I'm sayin'.
Beatrix was torturing dragons
for power!
Which was terrible, of course.
Just didn't have
an energy crisis before,
is all I'm sayin'.
Starting a new government
and infrastructure is not easy.
[energy fritzing]
[groaning]
[crowd grumbling]
Seriously?
Ugh, another blackout?
[electricity crackling]
Third blackout this week!
Our temporary solves
clearly aren't doing enough.
[sighing] Because this old grid
is designed for dragon energy.
We need the time
for a complete conversion,
all while running streetlights,
public transportation,
the Energy Barrier--
That's it!
The Energy Barrier!
That barrier is a leftover
from Empress Beatrix.
Let's reroute that power
for the people's energy.
But with the Claws gone,
using that barrier
is Imperium's
only line of defense.
Who are we
defending ourselves from?
This is an era of peace!
Shut it down!
[crowd cheering]
Ah, looks like
that did the trick.
[crowd screaming in panic]
[screaming]
What is that thing?
[tentacles whipping]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪♪
[groaning weakly]
Come on, Riyu,
pull through.
[labored breathing]
[sipping weakly]
He took a direct hit
of whatever that monster
was blasting.
I've never seen a dragon
survive such a thing,
and I've seen a lot of dragons
in battle.
He's always been
a special dragon.
Do you think he could eat?
We make delicious
Umbrasylvan wheatcakes.
It's worth a shot, I guess.
Thank--Thank you
for all your help.
Thank you.
That dragon is a hero.
He saved our village--
You still tending
to that beast?
Riyu is not a beast,
he's one of us, a Ninja,
and you owe him your life,
you uptight wad.
By jove, I didn't realize
this subject would lead
to such crass name-calling.
Anyway,
I just wanted to let
everyone know
that monster is now
safely contained in our airship
for future study and display.
In case you were wondering.
I-I'll just...
see myself out then.
The Numbness.
The what?
[Wyldfyre]
When dragons are exposed
to a dangerous substance--
poisonous leffberries,
the spray
of a saber-toothed eel,
stuff like that--
they can get something
we call "The Numbness".
It's... usually fatal.
Usually?
I heard stories
of Dragon Elders
curing the Numbness
by converting a small amount
of whatever caused the problem
into an antidote.
Convert how?
I don't know!
I'm just telling you
what I heard.
Do I look like a dragon doctor?
So converting venom
could help his body's
natural defenses?
But he wasn't poisoned
by the venom
of a buck-toothed eel--
Saber-toothed.
--he was blasted by a monster!
Yeah, but that monster
looked like it was made
out of Elemental Energy.
So?
Look, before you joined
the team,
I didn't think
I had my own powers.
I thought Riyu gave them to me.
Weird, but okay.
Every time
I got a spark of power,
I could feel the energy
rolling through me,
like a wave.
[Riyu groaning softly]
Like a substance
that can affect the body.
Oh, so we reverse
that monster's energy somehow,
and give it back to Riyu?
Oh, so when she says it,
it sounds smart?
[blows a raspberry]
I just need to create something
that can convert
that kind of energy.
[Riyu groaning softly]
[Freya] We don't have much
advanced technology
in Umbrasylvis,
but what little we have gathered
is basically all here.
I hope it helps you save
the hero dragon.
Oh, wow, thank you.
[cracking joints, exhaling]
[energy sputtering]
Ugh.
How am I going to
get to do this
with our powers on the fritz?
[exhaling]
[energy sputtering]
[monster roaring]
Whoa!
[monster hissing]
-Hup!
-H'yah!
[grunting]
[monsters growling]
H'yah! Y'ah!
Ah!
[groaning in pain]
Y'ah!
[gasping]
[monsters growling]
[snarling]
[rotors whirring]
H'yah!
[♪♪♪]
[Zane] Surprise-surprise!
H'ah!
[Lloyd] Zane?
How did you find us?
[Zane] When my powers
got all janky...
...Pixal and I split up
to search for you all.
"J-Janky"?
[Zane]
I say "janky" now, Lloyd.
H'yah!
I was flying over these woods
and heard sounds of battle,
and guess who was
right at the center of it?
And I see you're dealing
with Elemental Monsters
in this land as well.
H'yah!
Oof!
They're in other places, too?
They're all-- Ugh!
--over the place,
and nearly unbeatable!
H'yah!
[energy sputtering]
[disembodied whispering]
[♪♪♪]
Ugh!
[Lloyd] Yes!
H'yah!
Powers are back again!
Again?
Y'ah!
H'yah!
Hup! Y'ah!
H'ah!
[Lloyd roaring]
Did we win?
I can sense trace readings
of their energies,
yet I think they've moved on,
but why are
our powers stable here?
[Lloyd] It won't last.
[energy sputtering]
I see.
What a bummer.
Zane, did you...
reprogram yourself or something?
"Bummer" didn't use to be
part of your vocab.
My time with Pixal
did wonders for my disposition.
Some might say
I'm more "chill,"
and when did you
rejoin the team, Arin?
[chuckling] Oh, man,
you've missed a lot!
[Lloyd] Including the reason
our powers are messed up.
We, uh, did something
that angered the Source Dragons,
so half of them
pulled their powers
from the Merged Lands.
I skip one adventure,
and the entire world
turns to chaos.
Hey, we're searching
for a way to fix it all.
Any interest
in helping us find something
called
the Temple of the Green Ninja?
[printer whirring]
[Kai] So, what even is
a "Department
of Vacation Simulation"?
[Jay] Administration employees
earn vacation days,
but aren't allowed
to actually go anywhere...
...so we--
I mean, they--
go up and sit
in Vacation Simulator chairs.
It tricks your brain
into thinking
you're at the beach,
the mountains,
an amusement park, whatever.
[Nya] So the Agents like that?
A Fake-Cation?
[Jay laughing] A "Fake-Cation!"
I should've thought of that one!
The Agents here
don't even know it's weird.
Land of Madness, remember?
[Nya] So how do we get there?
[Kai] Uh, the elevator, duh!
[Jay] That's how Agents
go up and down floors!
Don't be ridiculous.
[Kai] Don't have
to bite my head off.
Like you never had
any bad ideas.
[Jay] As far as I remember,
no, never.
[Kai scoffing]
[chuckling] When you get
your memories back,
you're in for a rude awakening.
[voice over P.A.]
Attention all Agents,
there are three Ninja
within the confines
of the building.
Please get
to the nearest safety station--
[Jay] "Safety Station"?
--because the highly efficient
Robo-Eliminators
are now online.
[groaning softly]
Our family doesn't have much,
but we made this
with what we have.
Thank you.
Gave up on your powers?
I built inventions by hand
long before I even knew
what an elemental power was.
He's sinking deeper
into the Numbness.
Whatever you're doing, Sora,
do it faster.
Got it!
I should be
a motivational speaker.
Time to collect
some Elemental Monster energy.
Let's go!
[tube suction hissing]
What the--?
[beating drum]
A speech is in order!
[clearing throat]
I'll give it.
[drum roll]
Members of
the Umbrasylvian Expedition,
congratulations on my--
our-- great victory!
Defeating an unknown monster
in open combat
and saving an innocent town!
Huzzah!
What?
Riyu did that!
Yes, yes, yes,
the dragon was helpful,
and certainly deserves
Honorable Mention,
but thankfully,
we were the ones
who contained the creature,
rendering it safe.
I built that containment unit.
And you did an excellent job...
of obeying me,
since I led you do to it.
-What!
-[sighing]
And now, thanks to my--
our skill,
we'll transport
this unparalleled
scientific discovery
to Ninjago,
where it can be put on display
for the benefit of all...
and the profit of me--
uh-- us!
Huzzah!
Ugh! We don't have time
for this!
[device powering up]
[snarling]
Excuse me.
I don't know what you're doing,
but that's property
of the Explorers Club,
and I forbid you
to interfere with it in any way.
[Frak] Dad?
We need this right now.
It could save Riyu's life.
Well, why didn't you say so?
Well, in that case,
we should enter negotiations
on how much to charge you
for access to--
[device beeping]
[monster grunting]
Done.
[sputtering] Okay, yes, uh,
you were only able to do that
because I gave you permission.
Permission granted!
[Zane] ...so I said to Pixal,
how was I to know
the Ampfedrox people
incubate their offspring
in containers
that look like teacups?
She laughed
for 45 seconds straight,
and I laughed for 52 seconds.
It was quite an experience.
[Arin and Euphrasia laughing]
I'm... lost.
Let's take a break here.
Try to get our bearings.
[Arin] Sounds good to me.
[♪♪♪]
Remember when I was
too scared to admit
I had powers?
How could I forget?
Almost got eaten
by a giant octopus thing.
But now that my powers
don't work,
I'm scared that I can't protect
the Cloud Kingdom anymore.
There's more to self-defense
than powers.
Trust me, it's something
I'm very familiar with.
Yeah, but you're like
a Spinjitzu genius.
I could never do that.
I taught myself
basic Spinjitzu alone.
Maybe I could teach you?
Really?
If you'd like me to.
Okay, it starts with balance.
Try this first position.
H'ah!
[forest birds warbling]
Why are you squinting?
Trying to sense
where this temple could be.
By squinting?
By concentrating.
Ugh!
I don't even know
what I'm even doing!
Maybe your doubts
are clouding your senses.
Don't focus on them.
How do I just
not focus on doubts?
Sketch.
The forest, the rocks,
anything that comes to mind.
When did you get into art?
Art is like...
the opposite of you.
It's a way
of processing problems
without the constraints
of logic-based thinking.
Trying to get away from logic?
You?
Logic is an important
and powerful tool,
but I've learned
being too focused on it
can get in the way
of creative insights.
Wow, Zane.
This voyage with Pixal
really did have
an impact on you.
It did.
Love is also an important
and powerful tool.
[disembodied whispering]
If it helps,
think of drawing
as a form of meditation.
Pencil to the paper,
breathing.
[inhaling]
[disembodied whispering grows]
Huh.
I think it worked.
[♪♪♪]
Please work.
[injection hissing]
Why didn't you say anything?
What?
Your dad,
he took credit for everything,
and you just let him do it.
Look,
no one knows
how annoying he is
more than I do,
but growing up, in my house,
you didn't ever
disagree with him.
Speaking your mind?
Not acceptable.
But you're not a kid anymore.
No.
No, I'm not.
[groaning]
Well?
No change.
[♪♪♪]
[Eliminator 1] Ninja located?
[Eliminator 2] Negative.
[Eliminator 1] Ninja
must be located with efficiency
for purposes of...
elimination.
[together]
Eliminate! Eliminate!
[Kai] Uh, those things
are supposed to be
highly efficient?
[Jay] For this place,
absolutely.
Maybe they brought in
an outside
Efficiency Consultant?
We should be clear
if we just go around--
Ooh.
Funny thing!
Sometimes people think
we're Ninja,
but we're just Ninja cosplayers.
[chuckling awkwardly]
[Eliminator 3]
Sneaky Ninja lie... detected.
Eliminate! Eliminate!
[Sora] He just...
he needs to be okay.
This little guy changed my life.
Little?
He'll always be
a little guy to me.
[Riyu's breath wheezing]
No...
[wheezing]
Come on.
Wh-what?
He's not getting better.
Nothing's changing.
You said it would work.
I also said
I'm not a dragon doctor,
remember?
I-I just took a guess
at how much energy he needed.
Maybe he needs more?
We're losing him.
We need to keep trying
until it works.
We'll be right back.
[can rattling]
It's gone.
Someone opened
the Containment Unit
and let it out.
Who would--?
[nearby screaming]
[Eliminator 1] Locate Ninja.
Eliminate!
[Jay] Now!
Eliminate! Eliminate!
H'yah!
[beeping]
[Jay] Nya!
I'm thinking these bots
are overworked!
[Nya] Then it sounds like
they need a vacation!
[bots powering down]
Whee!
So, what Fake-Cation
did we send them on?
Uh...
the Land of Lee, Cavern Five.
Uh, Robots on waterslides?
How does that work?
As much as I'd love to ruminate
on the physics of robots
and water tubes,
we came here for a reason.
Oh...
Agent Donovan wasn't lying.
This equipment
that beams vacations
into people's brains
could be used
to block memories,
in theory.
Not in theory.
I'm proof,
but...
can you reverse it?
Of course she can.
You can, can't you, sis?
Maybe?
What are we waiting for?
Hold it.
This is risky.
I can't guarantee
it's gonna work.
So?
Then I don't get
my memories back?
Big deal.
I already don't have them.
No.
If this fails,
we could damage your brain,
making it impossible for you
to form new memories
ever again.
Like a permanent state
of amnesia?
[Nya] Yes.
Doesn't matter.
Let's do it.
Jay, think this through.
You're here, with us,
back on the team.
You can relearn Spinjitzu.
We can make new memories,
better than the old ones.
He's right.
You're still the Jay I love
even without your memories.
You know why I have to do this.
I had a whole life,
apparently a whole
wonderful life,
with all of you,
and I can't go on another moment
without remembering it.
This might hurt.
[typing rapidly]
[♪♪♪]
[screaming]
Turn it off.
Turn it off!
It's hurting him!
I think this is how it works!
[♪♪♪]
[screaming]
[machine powering down]
Oh no...
Oh no!
[Kai's voice muffled] Jay?
You with us, buddy?
[♪♪♪]
I'll take that as a yes.
[smooching noises]
All right, we get it.
That's enough.
[smooching noises]
Come on, dude, that's my sister!
So he heard whispers,
then drew a map?
I mean, don't get me wrong,
I'm a Writer of Destiny, but...
I'm not sure--
[Lloyd] We're here.
We are?
Whoa!
We are.
[disembodied whispering]
[♪♪♪]